# lehul Tanwa

Software Developer

□ mehultanwar.com

Ontario, Canada

**\( +1(782)234-0496** 

linkedin.com/in/mehultw in github.com/mehultw 9

github.com/mehultw-cs 👼

A passionate and creative Computer Scientist with 6+ years of experience in development, fluent in web technologies, generating solutions by analyzing clients' needs. Driven by a thirst for knowledge, novel experiences, embracing new challenges and learning opportunities with enthusiasm. Finds satisfaction from creating "something from nothing", adding new products and services that are user-friendly and of high quality.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Concentration: Co-Op (1 year)

Saint Mary's University - Halifax, Canada

- Digital Logic and Architecture Data Structures and Algorithms

Software Engineering

- AR/VR & Human-Computer Int. Artificial Intelligence
- Principles of Programming Lang.

- Sept 2021
- Info Vis. Interaction
- Data Mining
- Mobile App Development

# **SKILLS**

- Strong organizational and management skills developed through organizing, managing and leading teams of students for both academics and volunteering
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills, presenting to the public on science, technology, entrepreneurial and related topics, translating complex information into understandable terms
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, WordPress, NextJs. Fluent in data representation with D3, Python, R. Development technologies in use include Docker, Cloudflare, Netlify, Vercel, Git.

# Languages

Java Python JavaScript

★ NextJS <sup>®</sup> ReactJS <sup>N</sup> MySQL

**∃** HTML5/CSS3 **Ŵ** WordPress

₩ Webflow PHP SD3 # C#

# **Technologies**

Shopify Docker

Google Cloud Platform

Divi Theme Engine " Vercel

CloudFlare Y Netlify

# Tools

VSCode **€** MacOS **♦** Git

₩ Windows 🐧 Linux >- Zsh

Figma Adobe Suite

**€** Microsoft Suite ■ Proxmox

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Project Manager, Technology (Part-time)

Saint Mary's University Entrepreneurship Center – Halifax, Canada

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

SMUEC helps start new businesses in Nova Scotia through consulting and social entrepreneurship. Maintained and developed websites while meeting any technological needs the organization had while studying full time.

- Maintained and developed websites and met most technological needs of the organization while studying fulltime
- Produced webpages for events, marketing businesses, products, or services, along with informative pages for general consumption increasing interactivity and leading to greater engagement with clients by 1.5X
- Redesigned Website with modern looks and gradients including UI design, and programming following the latest security and WCAG guidelines creating reusable components with documentations for future teammates
- Consulting on tech requirements for various projects and facilitating smooth transition of personnel change, along with implementation of events such as "March Madness Pitch Competition" for a seamless in-person and virtual event

Technology Used: JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress, Divi, Figma

# Technology Assistant (Co-op 3) (Full-time)

Saint Mary's University Entrepreneurship Center – Halifax, Canada

Sept 2020 - Jan 2021

- Developed and managed web pages on SMUEC Website creating new content and keeping existing pages up to date
- Produced a New Business Intake form for web projects, using Qualtrics survey to collect vital data that aided in quick turnover for new web projects by up to 2.5X
- Provided Technical Support and Backend technological Architecture for Women In Business Conference using Whova client for conference and Zoom for conducting the event resulting in a smooth and adored event enjoyed by the community, awarding me a title of "Master of Puppets" for my behind-the-stage technology support by the organizers
- Consulted new business owners on e-commerce and developed a Shopify website as a result Technology Used: JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress, Shopify, Figma

# Web Developer, Technology Researcher, Support and Tester (Co-op 2) (Full-time)

Bloxo Inc. - Halifax, Canada

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Bloxo aimed to provide a digital platform (Mobile Application) that made scheduling sports events a breeze. This included finding people to play with and available fields or stadiums to host games/events.

- Developed all webpages with redesigned website UI for a modern look with gradients and transitions extending from mobile UI for consistent branding
- Designed/Architected a web page infrastructure for expanding web content to more than what the firm offered increasing the firm's market potential
- Performed QA, testing & surveys for mobile applications, providing recommendations for better UX in the next release of mobile applications along with any bugs or hurdles found while providing excellent customer service for all Bloxo users, increasing team efficiency by 25%
- Researched new technological applications, competitors, and other web applications to formulate business and technological expansion of the firm
- Created content for marketing including photography and cinematography products leading to targeted product placement in market and community

Technology Used: jQuery, JavaScript, Webflow, Webflow CMS, Stripe, Firebase

# ITSS Help Desk Staff (Now EIT) (Part-time)

Saint Mary's University - Halifax, Canada

Apr 2017 – Jan 2020

Resolved customer (SMU Faculty, Staff, and students), issues and services through being the first point of contact, troubleshooting and transferring requests to different departments in ITSS as required

- Received countless glowing recommendations from SMU personnel showing exceptional service which included going beyond the job description to meet and exceed customer satisfaction on several occasions
- Kept up to date with enterprise software to be deployed, with high-security practices, helping mitigate phishing attempts, and keeping the enterprise systems secure
- Maintained and created Knowledge-base articles for in-house and public viewing increasing technology awareness and accessibility for teammates and clients alike

Technology Used: TeamDynamix(Ticket Management), T4(Website), Papercut(Printing), Active Directory (Windows Admin)

# **Projects**

# Enactus Saint Mary's University Director Of Technology

Jan 2016 – May 2020 May 2018 – May 2019

Enactus is a student organization that solves community problems through social entrepreneurship. Appointed as Director to capture content, produce presentations, and make technical decisions for the organization.

- Managed all technology-related activities within Enactus Saint Mary's. including but not limited to content creation, photography, cinematography, and web development
- Developed and lead teams of volunteers to offer more technology-related volunteering opportunities like photography, cinematography, web development, content creation, and management skills along with guiding members on the above subject matters to improve upon services being provided

Represented Canada and Saint Mary's University at Enactus World Championship 2018 in California,
 U.S., and placed as Runner-up for Enactus Canada Nationals: Finalists; winning 5 awards during the event in May 2019.

#### **Technology Executive**

Jan 2016 – May 2020

Oversaw collection of data, created, and supervised presentations, created webpages, and produced photographs and videos used for education and to empower communities with social entrepreneurship

- Finalist at Enactus National Exposition in May 2016, May 2017, May 2018, May 2019 and May 2020
- Regional Championship Winner for Scotia Bank Youth Empowerment Challenge and Scotia Bank Eco Living
  Green Challenge in March 2017, March 2018 and presented the same in May 2017 and May 2018 at National
  expositions
- Represented Canada and Saint Mary's University on a global scale at Enactus Worlds 2017 on the challenge: "1 Race 2 end waste", held in London, England in September 2017
- Regional Championship Winner for Capitol One Financial Education Challenge in February 2016 and presented on the same at National Exposition in May 2016

#### Co-Founder - ConnectED Certification Program

May 2018 - May 2019

 Provide computer literacy and digital media education to youth who are driven by a thirst for knowledge and self-improvement

### Lead: Developer Student Club (DSC, Google)

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

Saint Mary's University - Halifax, Canada

Initialized, organized, and managed a club for individuals who solve community problems through technological means using ideation, brainstorming, product development, testing, and deployment by volunteering members eager to learn

- Club powered by Google Developers, and consists of Study Jams, workshops, Hackathons, and other events.
- Responsible for building society website & organize content. Help cultivate and inspire programming culture at SMU by working with other societies such as Math & CS Society at SMU.

#### **Board of Executives**

Sept 2019 – May 2020

Mathematics and Computer Science Society Saint Mary's University - Halifax, Canada MCSS provides a place of commune for Mathematics and Computer Science inclined individuals

- Help organize events, promote society, build applications, and conduct workshops.
- Responsible for building society website & organize content. Help cultivate and inspire programming culture at SMU by working with other societies such as DSC SMU.

# Service Canada Data Analytics Hackathon

Nov 2019

M.Sc. in Computing and Data Analytics, Saint Mary's University - Halifax, Canada

- Built an Artificial Intelligence powered data analysis software suite for a data analytics competition in under a week
- As the team with the least members (3) and the only undergraduate team in the competition, placed the First
  position in the competition held by Service Canada at Saint Mary's University. This project used deep neural
  networks, TensorFlow, Kesar, machine learning built using Python libraries and a jQuery, JavaScript web UI

### SURGE NeuroHackathon

Mar 2019

Dalhousie University - Halifax, Canada

- Acquired first place along with monetary remuneration for developing a Brain-Computer Interface that uses EEG sensors to detect brain wave patterns used as input to trigger events on a computer system
- Created an application using Python and Jupiter notebooks with extra libraries to demonstrate the
  technology by creating an alarm system that wakes a person as they are getting sleepy and automatically
  stops when they are awake





